NAACP Legal Defense and Educational Fund
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress
- Subject File, 1929-1968 (Box 38-175)
  - Transportation
    - Interstate Commerce Commission See also Containers 96-97, same heading
      - NAACP v. Saint Louis & San Francisco Ry., 1954-1956 See also Container 241, same heading (Box 162)
      - Printed material, 1945, 1954
      - Publicity and press releases, 1953-1955, undated
    - Melvin, Fletcher Hut, 1947-1951
    - Miscellany, 1947-1956, undated
  - Urban League, 1954-1961
  - Veterans Administration
    - Correspondence, 1946-1955, undated
    - Labor dispute, Tolly Broady, 1950-1951
    - Mountain Home Employees Association, 1955
    - Printed material, 1944-1952
  - Veterans' complaints
    - Individual cases
      - *Armstrong, Henry, 1953-1954
      - *Barnes, Stanley, 1951-1955
      - *Batchelor, LaFerena, 1951-1954 (Box 163)
      - *Blackman, Charlie, 1951
      - *Bowman, Walter Lee, 1955
      - *Brown, Albert, 1955-1956
      - *Brown, Charles, 1950-1954
      - *Cathey, James, 1952-1960
      - *Chambers, Jesse, 1954-1958
      - *Chappelle, John, 1956-1957
      - *Clark, Eddie, 1950-1952
      - *Clark, Ira, 1954-1955
      - *Daniels, Anthony, 1950-1956
      - *Davis, John, 1956-1960
      - *Ford, Ronald, 1954-1958
      - *Fuller, Lloyd, 1953
      - *Jones, Belton, 1957-1958
      - *Kirksey, John, 1954-1956 (Box 164)
      - Landes, Burton, 1953-1955
      - *Lemore, Erma, 1956-1957
      - *Lewis, Robert, 1957-1960
      - *Mitchell, John, 1951-1954
      - *Moutras, Norman, 1959-1960
      - Napier, George, 1960
      - *Peak, Charles, 1952-1955
      - *Peterson, Melvin, 1954-1955
      - *Sales, Charles, 1955-1960
      - *Simpson, Durrah, 1949-1960
      - *Sims, Robert, 1955
      - *Smith, Brisco, 1952-1953
      - *Spencer, Eugene, 1954-1955
      - *Turner, Thomas, 1953-1959, (2 folders)
      - *Wiggins, Samuel, 1955-1956 (Box 165)
      - *Wilkerson, Edward, 1956-1959
      - *Williams, Alonzo, 1955-1956
      - *Williams, Jerry, 1956-1960
      - *Wilson, Reginol, 1955
    - Miscellaneous cases
      - *A-B, 1950-1961, (6 folders)
      - *B-C, 1952-1961, (10 folders) (Box 166)
      - *D-F, 1950-1960, (5 folders) (Box 167)
      - *G-H, 1950-1960, (6 folders) (Box 168)
      - *H-J, 1951-1961, (8 folders) (Box 169)
      - *K-M, 1950-1962, (7 folders) (Box 170)
      - *N-R, 1954-1960, (8 folders) (Box 171)
      - *S-T, 1950-1960, (8 folders) (Box 172)
      - *U-Z, 1951-1960, (7 folders) (Box 173)
  - Veterans' hospitals
    - *Correspondence, 1950-1954
    - Press releases, 1950-1953
  - Veterans' housing, 1951-1952
  - Veterans' organizations
    - Correspondence, 1946-1951
    - Miscellany, 1950-1951, undated
  - Voter registration (Box 174)
    - Alabama
      - Bullock and Macon Counties, 1950-1954
      - Correspondence, 1950-1956, undated
      - Henry County, 1949-1951, undated
      - Mobile
        - Affidavits, 1944-1946
        - Correspondence, 1944-1946
    - Correspondence, 1936-1959
    - Miscellany, 1950-1958, undated
    - Mississippi
      - Correspondence, 1956-1957
      - Darby v. Daniels, 1957-1959 See also Container 194, same heading
      - Forrest County
        - Affidavits, 1952-1956
        - Correspondence, 1952-1957
    - North Carolina
      - Affidavits, 1936-1940, undated
      - Correspondence, 1936 (Box 175)
      - Lassiter v. Northampton County Bd. of Elections, 1957-1959 See also Container 231, same heading
  - Wallace, Fred, Voter Education Project, 1967-1968 See also Oversize
  - Waring, J. Waties
    - Correspondence, 1950-1952
    - Miscellany, 1950-1953, undated
  - *Weaver, Maurice M., 1952
  - Welfare assistance
    - *Correspondence, 1945-1954
    - Miscellany, 1947-1953
  - Wesley, Carter, 1948-1950
  - Worker's Defense League, 1950-1953
  - Wright, Herbert, 1954-1955
  - Wright, Louis T., memorial, 1953
  - Wyland, Ben
    - Correspondence
      - 1956
      - 1957-1959
    - Miscellany, 1950-1952, undated
- Legal Case File, 1915-1967 (Box 176-264)
  Records of NAACP Legal Defense and Educational Fund litigation, including correspondence, memoranda, notes, newspaper clippings, printed matter, briefs of cases, petitions, writs, affidavits, depositions, exhibits, legal memoranda, resolutions, orders, judgments, and trial or hearing transcripts.
  Arranged alphabetically by case name. A partial card index to cases, 1956-1964, is filled at the beginning of the series. Cases with multiple folders are further organized by general record type: correspondence, background material, legal documents, printed case records, and related case material for records of a lower court, counter actions, and test cases. A parenthetical note after each case name indicates the type of case (e.g., criminal law, education, housing) and the state in which the litigation took place. For category descriptions and a list of cases by category and state, see the index.
  - Index, 1956-1964 (Box 176)
  - Abbington v. Board of Education of Louisville, Ky., undated (education, Ky.)
  - Abernathy v. Izzard, 1955 (education, Ark.)
  - Acheson v. Murakami, 1949 (miscellaneous: citizenship of Nisei, Calif.)
  - Adams v. Maryland, 1953 (criminal law, Md.)
  - Adler v. Board of Education of the City of New York, 1951 (miscellaneous: communist teachers barred, N.Y.)
  - Afro-American Co. v. Owen (miscellaneous: free press, Md.)
    - Correspondence and background material, 1957
    - Printed records, 1957
    - Related case, Owen v. Afro-American Co., 1956
  - Alabama v. Allen, 1964-1965 (civil rights protest demonstrations, Ala.)
  - Alabama v. Fikes, 1953 (criminal law, Ala.)
  - Alabama v. Gray, 1964 (civil rights protest demonstrations, Ala.) (Box 177)
    - 1 of 7
    - 2 of 7
    - 3 of 7
    - 4 of 7
    - 5 of 7
    - 6 of 7
    - 7 of 7 (Box 178)
  - Alabama v. Hanson, 1963 (civil rights protest demonstrations, Ala.)
  - Alabama v. Johnson (public accommodations, Ala.; also civil rights protest demonstrations)
    - Correspondence and background material, 1964-1965
    - Legal documents, 1963-1964
    - Related cases
      - Duncombe v. Alabama, 1963
      - Montgomery v. Alabama, 1963
  - Alabama v. Robinson, 1963 (civil rights protest demonstrations, Ala.)
  - Alabama v. Tuskegee Civic Ass'n, 1957 (civil rights protest demonstrations, Ala.)
  - Alexander v. Texas, 1954 (labor, Tex.) (Box 179)
  - Allen v. Louisiana State Bd. of Education, 1961 (education, La.)
  - Allen v. Masters, 1952 (education, Tex.)
  - Amer v. Superior Court of Calif., 1947 (housing, Calif.)
  - American Jewish Congress v. Arabian Amer. Oil Co., 1959 (labor, N.Y.)
  - Anderson v. Board of Education of the County of Mercer, W.Va., 1955 (education, W.Va)
  - Andrews v. Cook, 1955 (education, Ga.)
  - Angel v. Louisiana State Bd. of Education, 1956 (education, La.)
  - Arnaud v. Arnaud's Restaurant, 1964 (public accommodations, La.)
  - Arrington v. Alabama (criminal law, Ala.)
    - Correspondence and background material, 1950
    - Legal documents, 1949-1950
  - Ashley v. School Bd. of Gloucester County, 1949 (education, Va.)
  - Askew v. Benton Harbor Hous. Comm'n (housing, Mich.)
    - Background material, 1955
    - Correspondence, 1951-1956
    - Legal documents, 1955-1956
  - Atkins v. Matthews, undated (education, Tex.) (Box 180)
  - Avent v. North Carolina (civil rights protest demonstrations, N.C.)
    - Correspondence, 1960-1962
    - Background material
      - 1962
      - Notes and drafts, 1962, undated
    - Legal documents and printed records, 1962
    - Related case, North Carolina v. Avent
      - Legal documents, general, 1960
      - Transcript, 1960
  - Avery v. Wichita Falls Indep. School Dist. (education, Tex.)
    - Correspondence, 1956
    - Legal documents, 1956
  - Ayer v. Mann, 1949 (education, Ill.)
  - Bacon v. Local 9, Bricklayers and Tile Setters Union, 1949 (labor, Calif.)
  - Bailey v. Smith, circa 1953 (recreation, Kan.)
  - Bailey v. Virginia, 1950 (criminal law, Va.)
  - Bailey v. Wilkins (miscellaneous: NAACP branch dispute, N.Y.) (Box 181)
    - Correspondence and background material, 1950-1951
    - Legal documents, 1950-1951
      - 1 of 2
      - 2 of 2
  - Banks v. Alabama (civil rights protest demonstrations, Ala.)
    - Legal documents, 1963-1964
    - Related case, Allen v. Alabama, 1963
  - Banks v. Housing Auth. of the City and County of San Francisco, Calif. (housing, Calif.)
    - Correspondence
      - 1952
      - 1953
    - Legal documents, 1952
    - Printed records, 1953
  - Barkley v. Tennessee, undated (criminal law, Tenn.) (Box 182)
  - Barnes v. City of Gadsden, Ala. (housing, Ala.)
    - Correspondence
      - 1957-1958
      - 1959
    - Background material, 1953, 1958, undated
    - Legal documents
      - General file, 1958-1959
      - Exhibits, 1958
      - Transcripts, 1958-1959
    - Printed records, 1958-1959
  - Barrett v. Jewett, 1950 (criminal law, Va.) (Box 183)
  - Barrows v. Jackson, 1950-1952 (housing, Calif.)
  - Bates v. Batte (education, Miss.) See also Container 159, same heading
    - Correspondence
      - 1947-1948
      - 1949-1951
    - Background material
      - Memoranda and notes, 1948-1949, undated
      - Reports, drafts, and clippings, 1949-1951
    - Legal documents
      - General file, 1948-1950
        - 1 of 3
        - 2 of 3
        - 3 of 3 (Box 184)
      - Transcript, 1949
    - Printed records
      - 1950, undated
      - Transcript, 1950
  - Batterson v. Omaha Post Number One of the Am. Legion, 1948 (miscellaneous: communists excluded from organization, Neb.)
  - Battle v. Wichita Falls Junior College, 1951-1953 (education, Tex.)
  - Beal v. Holcombe, 1951 (recreation, Tex.)
  - Beauharnais v. Illinois, 1952 (miscellaneous: free press, Ill.)
  - Becknell v. Trig Inc., 1957 (public accommodations, Kans.)
  - Bell v. Board of Educ., Amityville, N.Y., 1955-1956 (education, N.Y.)
  - Benjamin v. Louisville & Nashville R.R., circa 1944 (labor, Ky.) (Box 185)
  - Betts v. Easley, 1946 (labor, Kans.)
  - Bishop v. Doyle, 1948 (education, D.C.)
  - Bishop v. Statler Hotels, 1957 (public accommodations, Mich.)
  - Blount v. School Bd. of Isle of Wight County, Va., undated (education, Va.)
  - Blue v. Durham Public School Dist., 1949 (education, N.C.)
  - In re Board of Education, Union Free School Dist. 9, Town of Hempstead, N.Y., 1949-1950 (education, N.Y.)
  - Board of Supervisors of La. State Univ. v. Tureaud, 1955 (education, La.)
  - Boldan v. Allen, 1964 (public accommodations, Fla.)
  - Booker v. Tennessee Bd. of Educ. (education, Tenn.)
    - Background material
      - 1955-1956
      - Notes and drafts, 1955, undated
    - Legal documents and printed records
      - General file, 1955-1957
      - Transcript, 1955
  - Borrough v. Jenkins, 1955 (education, Okla.)
  - Bowler v. School Bd. of the City of Richmond, 1942 (education, Va.) (Box 186)
  - Boyd v. Board of Control of Fla. (education, Fla.)
    - Correspondence, 1949-1951
    - Legal documents, 1949-1950
    - Related cases, Florida ex rel. Maxey; Hawkins; Lewis; etc. v. Board of Control of Fla., 1949-1950
  - Boyer v. Garrett, 1948 (recreation, Md.)
  - Boynton v. Virginia, 1959-1960 (public accommodations, Va.; also transportation)
  - Bradshaw v. Whigam, 1965-1966 (public accommodations, Va.)
  - Breslow v. Wilson (education, N.Y.)
    - Background material
      - Clippings, etc., 1949, undated
      - Memoranda, notes
    - Legal documents
      - 1948-1949
      - 1950
      - Legal documents and printed records, 1951
  - Brewer v. Hoxie School Dist. No. 46 of Lawrence County, Ark. (education, Ark.)
    - Background material, 1955
    - Printed records, 1956
    - Related case, Hoxie School Dist. No. 46 of Lawrence County, Ark. v. Brewer, 1955
  - Bright v. NAACP, 1951 (miscellaneous: NAACP finances, N.Y.)
  - Bright v. Union Parish School Bd., 1954 (education, La.)
  - Brooks v. City School Bd. of Galax, Va., 1959 (education, Va.)
  - Brown v. Baldi (criminal law, Pa.) (Box 187)
    - Background material and legal documents, 1953-1954
    - Printed records, 1954
  - Brown v. Board of Educ. of Calvert County, Md., 1937 (education, Md.)
  - Brown v. Board of Trustees, Lagrange Independent School District, 1951 (education, Tex.)
  - Brown v. County Court of Kanawha County, W.Va., circa 1959 (public accommodations, W.Va., also transportation)
  - Brown v. Hanna, 1945 (transportation, W.Va.)
  - Brown v. Long, 1957 (education, Okla.)
  - Brown v. Ramsey, 1948-1949 (education, Ark.)
  - Brown v. S.C. Elec. and Gas Co., 1956 (transportation, S.C.)
  - Brown v. Southern R.R. Co., 1947 (transportation, Va. and other southern states)
  - Brown v. Union Free School District No. 16, Nassau County, N.Y., 1951 (education, N.Y.)
  - Bruce v. Stilwell, 1954 (education, Tex.)
  - Bryan v. Austin, 1956-1957 (education, S.C.)
  - Bryant v. Mayor and City Council of Baltimore, 1950 (recreation, Md.)
  - Buchanan v. Warley; Harris v. Louisville, 1915-1926 (housing, Ky.)
  - Bulah v. Gebhart, 1950-1951 (education, Del.)
  - Burkman v. Liddy, 1942 (housing, Calif.)
  - Burleigh v. Weakley, 1956 (education, Calif.)
  - Burns v. Wilson (armed forces; also criminal law) See also Container 147, same heading (Box 188)
    - Correspondence
      - 1949, Jan.-May
      - 1949, July-1950, Feb.
      - 1950, Apr.-1952, undated
    - Background material, undated
    - Legal documents and printed records, 1952-1953
    - Related cases
      - Burns v. Lovett, 1949-1952
        - 1 of 2
        - 2 of 2
      - Dennis v. Lovett, 1952 (Box 189)
        - 1 of 2
        - 2 of 2
  - Burroughs v. Sanitary Dist. of Chicago, 1951 (public accommodations, Ill.)
  - Burt v. Foust, 1950 (miscellaneous: exclusion from American Bowling Congress, Ohio)
  - Butler v. Matthews, 1950 (education, Tex.)
  - Butler v. Wilemon, 1949 (education, Tex.)
  - Byars v. White, 1955-1956 (recreation, Tex.)
  - Byrd v. Brice, 1952 (elections, La.)
  - Byrd v. City of New Orleans, 1948 (civil rights protest demonstrations, La.)
  - Cains v. Green, 1953 (education, Tex.)
  - Camp v. Recreational Bd. for the District of Columbia, 1951 (recreation, D.C)
  - Capel v. Shaw, 1949 (criminal law, N.Y.)
  - Carr v. Cole, 1957 (education, Okla.)
  - Carson v. Board of Educ. of McDowell Co., N.C., 1955-1957 (education, N.C.) See also same Container, Carson v. Warlick
  - Carson v. Warlick, 1956 (education, N.C.) See also same Container, Carson v. Board of Educ. of McDowell Co., N.C.
  - Carter v. City of Birmingham, 1965 (civil rights protest demonstrations, Ala.)
  - Carter v. School Bd. of Arlington County, Va., 1950 (education, Va.)
  - Cassell v. Texas, 1949 (criminal law, Tex.) (Box 190)
  - Castle Hill Beach Club, Inc., v. Arbury, 1955 (public accommodations, N.Y.)
  - Cavers v. Grasheim, 1961 (criminal law, N.Y.)
  - Chandler v. Fretag, 1952 (criminal law, Tenn.)
  - Christian v. Moore, 1952 (education, Tex.)
  - City of Birmingham v. Monk, 1950 (housing, Ala.)
  - City of Darlington v. Stanley, 1960-1961 (civil rights protest demonstrations, S.C.)
  - City of Jacksonville v. Watkins, 1946 (transportation, Fla.)
  - City of Montgomery v. Montgomery Improvement Ass'n, 1956 (public accommodations, Ala.)
  - City of Wichita v. Morton, 1948 (public accommodations, Kans.)
  - Civil Rights Congress of the City and County of San Francisco v. Warren, 1950 (criminal law, Calif.)
  - Clark v. Flory, 1956 (recreation, S.C.)
  - Clark v. Michigan, 1956 (criminal law, Mich.)
  - Clark v. Sandusky, 1951 (housing, Ill.)
  - Clemons v. Alabama, 1964 (civil rights protest demonstrations, Ala.)
  - Clemons v. Board of Educ. of Hillsboro, Ohio, (education, Ohio) (Box 191)
    - Correspondence, 1954-1956, undated
    - Background material, 1954, undated
    - Legal documents, 1954-1956
    - Printed records, 1955, undated
  - Cohen v. Public Hous. Admin. (housing, Ga.)
    - Correspondence, 1956-1959
    - Background material, 1952-1957
      - 1 of 2
      - 2 of 2
    - Legal documents and printed records, 1957
    - Related case, Heyward v. Public Hous. Admin. (Box 192)
      - Legal documents, 1952-1956, 1 of 2
      - Legal documents, 1952-1956, 2 of 2
      - Printed records, 1954-1955, undated
  - Coke v. City of Atlanta (public accommodations, Ga.; also transportation)
    - Correspondence, 1958-1960
    - Legal documents, 1959, undated
  - Colbert v. Coney Island (public accommodations, Ohio)
    - Legal documents, 1953-1955, undated
    - Related cases, 1954-1956
  - Combre v. John McNeese State College, 1954 (education, La.) (Box 193)
  - Commings v. City of Charleston, 1960-1961 (recreation, S.C.)
  - Commission against Discrimination v. Pelham Hall Apts., Inc., 1957-1958 (housing, N.Y.)
  - Commission on Civil Rights ex rel. Tilley v. International Bhd. of Elec. Workers Local 35; Commission on Civil Rights ex rel. Stewart v. International Bhd. of Elec. Workers Local 35, 1951 (labor, Conn.)
  - Conley v. Wilkin, 1950 (education, Ill.)
  - Connecticut v. Higgs, 1953-1955 (criminal law, Conn.)
  - Constantine v. Southwestern La. Inst., 1954 (education, La.)
  - Cook v. Board of Educ. of Prince George's City, Va., 1938-1940 (education, Va.)
  - Corbin v. Board of Educ. of Pulaski County, Va., 1949-1950 (education, Va.)
  - Covington v. Edwards, 1955-1959 (education, N.C.) See also Container 140, same heading
    - Background material, 1958-1959
    - Legal documents and printed records, 1955-1959
  - Crawford v. Maher, 1952 (housing, N.J.)
  - Cruikshank v. Alabama, 1964 (civil rights protest demonstrations, Ala.)
  - Curators of the Univ. of Mo. v. Bell, 1950 (education, Mo.) (Box 194)
  - Daniels v. North Carolina (criminal law, N.C.)
    - Background material, 1949-1950
    - Legal documents, 1949-1950
  - Darby v. Daniel (elections, Miss.) See also Container 174, same heading
    - Background material, 1954-1957, undated
    - Legal documents
      - General file, 1957-1958
      - Deposition, 1958
      - Transcript, 1958
  - Dargon v. Yellow Cab Co. of Pittsburgh, 1952 (labor, Pa.)
  - Davis v. Arn (labor, Ala.) (Box 195)
    - Correspondence, 1950-1953
    - Background material, undated
    - Legal documents, 1951-1952
    - Printed records, 1952
  - Davis v. Cook (education, Ga.) See also Container 158, same heading
    - Correspondence, 1947-1950
    - Background material, 1944-1950, undated
      - 1 of 3
      - 2 of 3
      - 3 of 3
    - Legal documents
      - General file, 1943-1948
        - 1 of 3
        - 2 of 3 (Box 196)
        - 3 of 3
      - Transcripts
        - 1947, Nov. 10-12
        - 1947, Nov. 13-14
        - 1947, Nov. 17-18
        - 1948, Dec.
    - Printed case records, 1949
  - Davis v. Saint Louis Hous. Auth. (housing, Mo.)
    - Correspondence, 1953-1956
    - Background material, 1953-1954
    - Legal documents, 1953-1956 (Box 197)
  - Davis v. Schnell, 1949 (elections, Ala.)
  - Davis v. Schultz, 1955 (education, Ill.) See also Container 132, same heading
  - Dawson v. Farnsley, circa 1950 (education, Ky.)
  - Dawson v. Mayor and City Council of Baltimore, Md. (recreation, Md.)
    - Background material, 1947-1955, undated
    - Legal documents, 1952-1956
    - Printed records, 1954, undated
    - Related cases
      - Issacs v. Mayor and City Council of Baltimore, 1955-1956
      - Lonesome v. Maxwell; Lonesome v. Peverley, 1952-1954
      - Mayor of Baltimore v. Dawson, 1955
  - Day v. Atlantic Greyhound Corp., 1948 (transportation, Va.)
  - DeAngelis v. Board of Liquor License Comm'rs for Baltimore, Md., circa 1955 (miscellaneous: liquor licensing, Md.)
  - Delgado v. Bastrop Indep. School Dist., 1948 (education, Tex.)
  - Dembo v. Siple, 1952 (miscellaneous: veterans' cemetery)
  - Department of Conservation & Dev. v. Tate, 1956 (recreation, Va.)
  - Derrick v. Local 470, International Union of Operating Eng'rs, 1951-1952 (labor, S.C.) (Box 198)
  - Detiege v. New Orleans City Park Improvement Ass'n, 1949-1951 (recreation, La.)
  - Diamond v. Louisiana (civil rights protest demonstrations, La.)
    - Legal documents and printed records, 1963-1964
    - Related case, Louisiana v. Clemmons, 1962
  - District of Columbia v. John R. Thompson Co., Inc., 1950-1953 (public accommodations, D.C.)
  - Dorsey v. Stuyvesant Town Corp., 1947-1948 (housing, N.Y.)
  - Dukes v. Hanna, 1952-1954 (criminal law, N.J.)
    - 1 of 2
    - 2 of 2
  - Dunn v. Board of Educ. of Greenbrier, W.Va., 1955 (education, W.Va.)
  - Earle v. Greenville County and Pickens County, S.C., 1949 (miscellaneous: lynching, S.C.), 1955
  - Easterly v. Dempster, 1952 (recreation, Tenn.)
  - Eaton v. Board of Educ. of New Hanover County, N.C., 1953 (education, N.C.)
  - Eaton v. Board of Managers of James Walker Memorial Hospital, 1956 (public accommodations, N.C.)
  - Eleby v. Louisville Mun. Hous. Comm'n, 1956-1957 (housing, Ky.)
  - Elliott v. Cumberland County Bd. of Elections, 1955 (elections, N.C.) (Box 199)
  - Elmore v. Rice, 1947 (elections, S.C.)
  - English v. Pasadena School Bd., 1953 (education, Calif.)
  - Enoch Pratt Free Library v. Kerr, 1945 (labor, Md.)
  - Everett v. Smith, 1949-1950 (education, Ga.)
  - Evers v. Dwyer, 1958 (transportation, Tenn.)
    - Legal documents, central file
    - Transcript
  - Fikes v. Alabama, 1953-1956 (criminal law, Ala.)
    - Correspondence, 1953-1956
    - Background material, 1953-1956, undated
    - Legal documents, 1954-1956
      - 1 of 2
      - 2 of 2
  - Fleeks v. Stilwell, 1949 (education, Tex.)
  - Fleming v. Garrison, 1955 (recreation, Tex.)
  - Flemming v. South Carolina Elec. and Gas Co., 1954-1956 (transportation, S.C.) See also Container 160, same heading (Box 200)
  - Fletcher v. Coney Island, Inc., 1954-1956 (public accommodations, Ohio)
  - Florida ex rel. Hawkins v. Board of Control, 1950-1958 (education, Fla.)
    - Background material, 1946-1949, undated
    - Legal documents
      - 1950-1957
      - 1958, undated
    - Printed records, 1951-1956
  - Florida v. Jordan, 1951 (criminal law, Fla.) (Box 201)
  - Flowers v. National Hous. Auth., 1943 (housing, Mich.)
  - Foeller v. Housing Auth. of Portland, 1953 (housing, Ore.)
  - Foister v. Board of Supervisors of La. State University and Agricultural and Mechanical College, 1951 (education, La.)
  - Fowlkes v. Alabama, 1964 (civil rights protest demonstrations, Ala.)
  - Franklin v. Harber, 1949 (elections, Ga.)
  - Franklin v. Housing Auth. of the City of Sacramento, 1952 (housing, Calif.)
  - Freeman v. School Bd. of Chesterfield Co., 1948 (education, Va.)
  - Freret Civic Improvement Ass'n v. Orleans Parish School Bd., 1952 (education, La.)
  - Froneberger v. Huss, 1954 (education, N.C.)
  - Furlow v. Florida, 1965 (criminal law, Fla.)
  - Gatlin v. McDaniel, 1950 (elections, Ark.)
  - Gaynor News Co. v. National Labor Relations Bd., 1952-1953
  - Georgia v. Henderson, 1950 (criminal law, Ga.)
  - Georgia v. Ingram, 1948 (criminal law, Ga.)
  - Georgia v. Walker, 1966 (criminal law, Ga.)
  - Girard Estate, Orphan's Court of Philadelphia, 1955 (education, Pa.)
  - Goins v. School Bd. of Grayson County, Va., undated (education, Va.)
  - Goss v. Board of Educ. of Knoxville, Tenn., 1958-1961 (education, Tenn.) See also Container 142, same heading
  - Grant v. Taylor, 1954-1955 (education, Okla.)
  - Ex parte Gray, 1951 (education, Tenn.) (Box 202)
  - Gray v. Board of Trustees of the Univ. of Tenn. (education, Tenn.)
    - Correspondence and background material, 1951, undated
    - Legal documents, 1951-1952
      - 1 of 2
      - 2 of 2
    - Printed records, 1951
  - Gray v. Main (elections, Ala.) (Box 203)
    - Background material
      - Voting and population records, Barbour, Bullock, Greene, and Macon counties, 1961-1966
        - Card files
          - Box 1
          - Box 2 (Box 204)
          - Box 3 (Box 205)
          - Box 4 (Box 206)
          - Box 5 (Box 207)
          - Box 6 (Box 208)
          - Box 7 (Box 209)
          - Box 8 (Box 210)